As we look back at some of our logo
you're going to lightning speed, dude.
I'm Chris and today I want to talk to
you about three ways three ways you can
improve your design. As we look back at
some of our logo critiques, we kept
noticing consistent issues popping up,
right? I'm going to play some clips.
After the clips, we'll do a quick
breakdown and talk about how you can
avoid these three common mistakes and
hopefully improve your design.
So, here's his logo. This one's coming
from Bao Weiding Win. It's using, I
believe, Futura. It's trident and he's
got two bars on the top and the bottom.
Now, this feels really nice to me.
Here's what I like about this. There's a
graphic element, so it feels like a
symbol, but I can read it and it's well
integrated. What I don't like about it
is where the bars on the top and the
bottom of the tride land. The way that
you say it is trident, so I wanted to
emphasize one syllable or the other.
So, we don't want to use graphic
elements purely for decoration. We want
to reinforce and make the logo even more
legible. So, next up is Hoodlum done by
Ashlyn Harris. Logo created for Hoodlum,
a clothing line for the people who don't
fit in with the rest. I like this
lockup. You're trying to get everything
nice and tight and that's a good thing.
Although, I don't necessarily love the
modifications that you made. I don't
like how the L and the U come together
because the way that these sans serif
typefaces terminate, it's with a
straight line, right? So, when you first
of all, put it on an angle and you kind
of follow the curvature of the U, it
just makes it look like that letter form
is from some other typeface. The other
thing is you've kind of cut off the H,
basically the bottom of the H and put a
bar across. I like that as a visual
element, but you're also making the H
very hard to read. Somebody might look
at that and see it as a symbol, like
some kind of abstract crown or
something, and then read it as Udlam.
So, legibility should supersede any kind
of decorative element that you do. Next
up is from Roberto Ramos. The name of my
brand is Avi. The three eyes is the
three-point line half court line and the
other three-point line. Okay, first of
all, I like this mark. It does feel a
little bit like retro 80s logo. Pretty
cool. Except for I thought it read
audio. a u d i o and then when I read it
was for Avi, I was thinking this isn't
read as Avi at all.
Yeah, it doesn't.
No, I thought it was audio as well.
Right? It would be a pretty good mark
for audio. Okay,
good mark and you guys please please
please make sure it reads. Reading the
your word mark on your logo is very
important. It supersedes all the other
decisions that you're making. All right,
this is from Jake Goosen. It's a book
and it's a worm. Uh-huh. It works. So,
here's where maybe the type pairing with
the mark feels a little bit off. A lot
of you guys are really good at drawing
symbols. I think you just need to learn
how to pair it with a different typeface
and the lockup is important. Here's
where I'm thinking you can play around
with mixing two weights where you do
book in a lighter weight and then warm
is in a bolder typeface. Mhm. Yeah.
Break it up. Next up, Jacob Keelan. My
take on a driverless car logo. Oh,
interesting. It's an exploration of the
GPS symbol. Ooh. It does feel like
automotive. It's got that nice kind of
chevron crest shape paired with a nice
bold sans serif typeface. It has this
point which is that reads like the
letter A. So, I'll autonome, it makes
sense to me and it's also a navigation
system. So, that's the point you're
pointing north. Those are two good
things and it's not illustrating like we
talked about this before. You don't want
to illustrate what it does. You don't
want to show a guy like giving you
directions.
It's it's abstract, but it's clear what
it is. It reminds me of Tesla a little
bit. Actually, it reminds me of Star
Trek. Everybody going to be reminded of
something here. So, the natural thing is
to compare always. And designers are
like famous for comparing things. This
is both good and bad. I I like to look
at things for what they are because I
always feel like everything's already
been done. And as long as there's not a
navigation system that looks just like
this, I'm good with that. Cuz you know,
you can't own a triangle. You can't own
a square or trapezoid cuz it's for
everybody to use. That's true. I wasn't
saying it was a bad thing though.
No, I wasn't saying you said it. I'm I'm
reacting to like how people always It's
just like that. And then people dismiss
it.
Uh-huh. And then they make something
really ugly.
Yeah. Okay, so let me share with you the
mistakes I saw and how to fix them.
Always work in black and white. No
colors, no textures. This will make it
easier for you to focus on the important
aspects of a logo. Things like
hierarchy, contrast, and legibility.
Legibility, legibility, legibility.
Not being able to read the logo, pretty
serious mistake. As you design your
logo, you are making lots of little
decisions, chopping letters, changing
fonts, etc. It's easy to get carried
away to the point in which the mark
becomes really difficult to read. The
solution? Always ask yourself, is it
legible? Does it read well? Legibility
should supersede every other
consideration. If you remember this, you
won't make the mistake of making your
logo hard to read.
Critiquing is an art. It's not that
anybody can just throw out a random
comment and think that somebody's going
to derive useful information. So, when
somebody asks you for your opinion, just
take a moment to think, to process, and
look at something. And try not to react
right off the bat. I like to think of it
like peeling an onion. Let me explain.
One, I start by simply describing what
I'm seeing. Just what's clearly there.
The typeface, the shapes, the curves,
the points, the line weights, etc. No
judgments. Then I start to notice how
certain things make me feel, and I
describe them using phrases like this
feels funny to me, or I like this.
Finally, having peeled back all the
layers, I feel the context has been set,
and I can start sharing ideas for or
that we can do to improve. Okay, there
you have it. Three common mistakes
designers make and how you can avoid
them. I hope you enjoyed this video and
you feel like you're a better designer
than you were 5 minutes ago. Want to
submit your logo for a critique? It's
pretty straightforward. Make sure you
follow us on Facebook @thefutureishere.
The future is spelled with no e, but you
should know that by now. All right, make
sure you guys like, comment, subscribe,
and hit that bell. Goodbye and see you
next time.